(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-24T23:38:20.821589",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
鷹嶺ルイ
[Takane Lui]
NEXT CHAPTER
鷹嶺ルイ 重大告知 LIVE
[Takane Lui Major Announcement LIVE]
四六時中帰りの会で
Always at the end-of-day meeting,
面倒くささを押し付けられている
all the annoying chores get pushed onto me.
何から何まで
From one thing to another,
私語は止めて まとめ役なら
stop chatting. If you're the leader,
真面目にうなずき合っている
listen well and nod along smoothly,
なかよしこよしで
all playing nice and friendly.
さあだだだ黙りたまえよ
Now sh-sh-shut the hell up!
言えないねそんな強い言葉は
I could never say such harsh words...
少しだけ静かにしてほしいね
I wish everyone would just be a little quiet.
私達大望へ
Toward our grand ambition,
世界転転転覆ヤヤヤ
world conquer-er-ers, yeah yeah yeah!
果たすその日まで
Until the day it comes true!
煉煉煉獄イェイイェイイェイ
In purg-purg-purgatory, yay yay yay!
あなたの周りもヨーヨーヨー
All around you is yo yo yo!
下界征服アレアレ ア
Conquering the lower world, ale ale a!
約束の地まで
To the promised land,
さあ掲げよばっテンばっテンてんてんてんてんてんてん僕ヤヤヤ
come on, raise it up, conquer-er-ers, yeah yeah yeah!
今日も議題そっちのけだね
Ignoring the agenda again today...
嫌になるから
I'm sick of this,
私一人でもやっておきますね
so I'll just handle it by myself.
全て全て全て任せて
Leave everything, everything, everything to me!
それもさせてよ
Let me handle that too,
大事なことなの
it's important.
わかっているでしょ
You understand, right?
四六時中帰りの会で
Always at the end-of-day meeting,
面倒くさいまま
stuck with all the annoyances,
今日も明日も過ぎて行くのでしょう
today and tomorrow will just keep passing by.
来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming!
一緒に歌ってー！
Sing along with us!
花瓶に水をあげましょう
Let's water the flower vase.
時の中萎れたこと忘れていた
I forgot that it had wilted with time.
さあだだだ黙りたまえよ
Now sh-sh-shut the hell up!
言えないねそんな強い言葉は
I could never say such harsh words...
少しだけ静かにしてほしいね
I wish everyone would just be a little quiet.
私達大望へ
Toward our grand ambition,
今と未来見たかったはずなのに
we were supposed to look at the present and future...
世界転転転覆ヤヤヤ
World conquer-er-ers, yeah yeah yeah!
見えぬその日まで
Until that unseen day!
滔滔滔々とえんえんえん
Endlessly, on and on and on!
この世の理ヨーヨーヨー
The rules of this world, yo yo yo!
今潜潜潜伏サササ
Now laying low-low-low!
あなたの街中形作るわ
We'll shape your town!
さあ世界転転転覆ヤヤヤ
World conquer-er-ers, yeah yeah yeah!
果たすその日まで
Until the day it comes true!
煉煉煉獄イェイイェイイェイ
In purg-purg-purgatory, yay yay yay!
あなたの周りもヨーヨーヨー
All around you is yo yo yo!
下界征服アレアレ ア
Conquering the lower world, ale ale a!
約束の地まで
To the promised land,
さあ掲げよばっテンばっテンてんてんてんてんてんてんとしならび
come on, raise it up as we stand side by side!
ヴィンテージのワインをあけましょう
Let me open up a bottle of vintage wine.
もういいじゃん ムキになっちゃって
Enough already, getting all worked up,
カッコつけて カッコよくない
trying to look cool when you're totally not.
そういうのイヤになってんだ
I'm so sick of all that stuff.
ほっといてよ 知りたくない
Just leave me alone, I don't wanna know.
もういいじゃん ヤケになってんの？
Enough already, are you being desperate?
嫉妬したり じっとできない
Getting jealous, unable to stay still.
聞こえないよう耳塞いだって
Even if I cover my ears so I can't hear,
言ってくるじゃん しんどいなあ
you still talk to me... This is so exhausting.
僕は誰も覗かないよ
I don't pry into anyone else's business,
だから僕のこと そっとしといて
so please just leave me alone.
うざいだけのバカにハイハイハイ
Saying 'yeah yeah yeah' to annoying fools,
ウケる またのお越し待ってるね
hilarious, 'looking forward to your next visit!'
だとか 本当は怯えてる
and all that, but honestly I'm terrified.
吠えるだけの弱虫だだだ
Just a coward who can only bark!
痛いくせに耐えてハイハイハイ
Enduring the pain, saying 'yeah yeah yeah,'
いつも平気なフリばっかなの 僕は
I'm always just pretending everything is fine.
壁を張ったまま笑う
Smiling while keeping my walls up,
それ以上近づかないででで
don't come any closer to me!
怖いじゃん
It's scary!
ばかばっか
Nothing but fools,
nothing but fools,
ばかばっか
やだ ばかばっか
I hate this, nothing but fools!
もういいじゃん まだ怒ってんの
Enough already, are you still mad?
ほっといてよ ホッとできない
Leave me alone, I can't even relax.
見ないように目を逸らしたって
Even if I avert my eyes to avoid looking,
付いてくるじゃん やっぱり
you still follow me around anyway.
転がったら起きればいいじゃん
If you trip, just get back up, right?
失ったら探せばいいじゃん
If you lose something, just search for it, right?
いやいやいやいやいやいやいや
No no no no no no no,
それでよくない？
isn't that good enough?
間違ったら直せばいいじゃん
If you make a mistake, just fix it, right?
嫌になったらやめればいいじゃん
If you hate it, just quit, right?
いやいやいやいやいやいやいや
No no no no no no no,
それでよくない？
isn't that good enough?
それで良くない？
Isn't that good enough then?
僕 誰も 覗かないよ
I won't peek at anyone,
だから 僕のこと そっとしといて
so just leave me alone.
嫌なこと全部大丈夫と言えたらいいのにな
If only I could say that all the bad stuff was fine,
思えたらいいのにな
if only I could feel that way.
違うよ デタラメな大正解
No, it's a nonsensical, perfect answer.
いつも僕はそんなロールなの
I'm always stuck in a role like that.
また言いたいこと殺すから もう忘れてくれ
I'm killing what I want to say again, so just forget about me.
うわっはっは うざいだけのバカにハイハイハイ
Uwahahaha! To the annoying fools, yeah yeah yeah.
ウケる またのお越し待ってるね
Hilarious! "Looking forward to your next visit," right?
だとか 本当は怯えてる
Or something like that—truth is, I'm terrified.
吠えるだけの弱虫だ だだだ
Just a coward who barks, y-y-yeah.
痛いくせ 耐えてはハイハイハイ
Even though it hurts, enduring it with a "yeah, yeah, yeah."
いつも平気なフリばっかなの
Always just pretending that I'm fine.
僕は壁を張ったまま笑う
I smile while keeping my walls up.
それ以上近づかないで とか
Saying "Don't come any closer than that."
ほんとーばっか いい加減ばっか とんだバグばっか だっせーなって
Nothing but fools, irresponsibility, and bugs... so lame.
そんなことばっか 思う僕もやっぱ どうしようもないんだ パッ
Thinking like that, I'm hopeless after all, bang!
罰点超過 痛いのとか耐えてらんないない
Penalty limit exceeded! I can't stand the pain, no, no.
死ねるって僕も口ばっかでね
Saying "I could die," I'm all talk too, right?
今日も壁を張ったまま笑う
Today as well, I smile while keeping my walls up.
それ以上近づかないで でで
Don't come any closer than that, d-d-
怖いじゃん ばかばっか
It's scary, isn't it? Nothing but fools.
ほら ばかばっか
See? Nothing but fools.
はい、ということで！重大告知ライブ始まりましたー！
Alright, and with that! The Major Announcement Live has begun!
皆さん、またまたね、HoloXの女幹部、鷹嶺ルイと申します！
Everyone, once again, I'm Takane Lui, executive officer of HoloX!
ということでみんな見えとるぞ、コメント。あ、拍手いっぱいありがとな！
So I can see all your comments! Ah, thanks for all the applause!
拍手いっぱいありがとう。ということで、本日のハッシュタグはこちら！
Thanks for all the applause. So, today's hashtag is this right here!
あ、こちらにありますね。
Ah, it's over here.
えー、ハッシュタグ #鷹嶺ルイ重大告知LIVE でたくさんつぶや…
Um... please post lots using the hashtag #TakaneLuiMajorAnnouncementLIVE...
あ、つぶやきじゃないわ！ポストして投稿してくれると嬉しいです！
Ah, not "tweet"! I'd be happy if you post with it!
みんな、今すぐポストしてください！
Everyone, please post right now!
ということで、もう1曲目、2曲目とね、『Overkill』、『ばかばっか』と
So, with the first and second songs, "Overkill" and "Baka Bakka",
えー、熱い曲が続いたんですけれども、1曲目からなんと！
um, we had hot songs in a row, and right from the first song...
特別ゲストが登場してくださいました！
...a special guest appeared for us!
ちょっとね、おしゃべりしたいと思いますので呼びたいと思います！
I'd like to chat a bit, so I'll call her out!
ベイちゃーん！
Bae-chan!
あれ？あれ？あれ？あれ？来たー！
Wait, huh? Huh? There she is!
わっさー！
Wassup!
我々はカオス！我々の果てなき混沌！降臨のインフィニティ！一石二鳥のバラ！汝の友、ホロENのハコス・ベールズです！
We are Chaos! Our endless chaos! Infinite advent! A rose of two birds with one stone! Your friend from HoloEN, Hakos Baelz!
ということでベイちゃんとはね、『Overkill』を一緒に歌わせていただいたんですけれども！
So, Bae-chan and I sang "Overkill" together!
めっちゃ嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
嬉しい！私も嬉しい！ベイちゃんとは…
Happy! I'm happy too! With Bae-chan...
本当に、あの、一緒に歌いたくて！
I really, um, wanted to sing together with you!
同じです！
Same here!
めっちゃ嬉しい！ / いや、ルイ姉の曲めっちゃ好きなんね！
I'm so happy! / No, I really love your songs, Lui-nee!
えー、嬉しい！ / ね、めっちゃかっこよくて。いやー、ようやく歌えましたね！
Aw, thank you! / Right, they're so cool. Man, we finally got to sing together!
歌えました！ / ね！ / 楽しかったー！
We did! / Right? / That was so fun!
『Overkill』ね、絶対ベイちゃんに合うと思って！
I thought "Overkill" would definitely suit you, Bae-chan!
やっぱカオスなんでね！ / いや、めっちゃかっこいい！
Because it's chaos after all! / Man, it was so cool!
いや、嬉しい、一緒に歌えて。 / ちょっとね…あの、最後のとこちょっとやらかした…
Man, I'm so happy we sang together. / Well, um... I kind of messed up at the very end...
え、嘘？
Eh, really?
だって、あの… / 全然わかんなかったよ、多分！
Because, well... / I bet no one noticed at all!
いや、多分ね、振りがね… / うん。
Well, maybe... the choreography, right? / Yeah.
言っていい、これ？ / いいよ！ / 振りは、元々無かったんだよね？
Can I say this? / Go ahead! / There was no choreography originally, right?
うん、うん、うん。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
で、なんかリハ中で「あ、ちょっと振り付けようか」みたいな話になってて…
And during rehearsal, we were like, "Ah, should we add a bit of choreography?"...
「うわー！やばい！」って、ちょっと最後のとこ忘れちゃって、すいません！
Like "Uwaah, oh no!", so I forgot the very end bit, I'm sorry!
全然、全然！全然わからなかった！でもやっぱりさ、テンション上がっちゃうとね…
Not at all! I couldn't tell at all! But when your excitement builds up, right...
わかるー！
I know, right!
いや、でも楽しんでくれたんだよね、きっとね！ / いや、めっちゃ楽しい！
Well, but you had fun, right? I'm sure of it! / Man, it was so much fun!
嬉しい！ / めっちゃくちゃ楽しい！
I'm happy! / It was super fun!
私もし、ベイちゃんの曲、本当に大好きで！
I really love your songs too, Bae-chan!
もういつかベイちゃんの曲も挑戦したいなーなんて…
I'd love to try singing your songs someday too...
ぜひぜひ！聞きたい！聞きたい！
By all means! I want to hear it! I want to hear it!
一緒に歌ってくれますか？
Will you sing with me?
いや、もうぜひです！いや、ルイ姉の『PSYCHO』聞きたいかも！
Oh, absolutely! Actually, I might want to hear Lui-nee sing "PSYCHO"!
え？
Eh?
『PSYCHO』聞きたいかも！
I want to hear "PSYCHO"!
『PSYCHO』ね！いや、『PSYCHO』難しいけど、えー、ぜひ一緒歌いましょう！
Ah, "PSYCHO"! "PSYCHO" is tough, but yeah, let me definitely sing it together!
歌いましょう！ / お願いします！ / お願いします！
Let's sing it! / Looking forward to it! / Looking forward to it!
ということで、21時半からですね、21時半頃にですね、重大告知を…
So, starting around 21:30, around 21:30 JST, the major announcement...
重大告知！ / させていただきますので…
Major Announcement! / ...will be made, so...
もう少しお待ちいただけますと幸いです！
we'd appreciate it if you could wait just a little longer!
Big announcement at 9:30 PM JST!
サンキュー！サンキューアロット！
Thank you! Thank you a lot!
海外アニキもね、返事してくれるんじゃないかな！大丈夫かな？
Overseas bros will probably respond to that too! Right?
ということで、この後はですね、事前収録で来ていただいたゲストさんのパートになりますので…
So after this, it'll be the part with the guests who pre-recorded for us,
一緒に、じゃあVTRのキュー振りしてもらってもいいですか、ベイちゃん？
so could you do the VTR cue with me, Bae-chan?
イエス！
Yes!
それでは皆さん、この後も楽しんでいってください！
Alright everyone, please keep enjoying the rest of the show!
せーの！
Ready, set...
VTR、どうぞー！
VTR, go!
単純で明快で簡単じゃない
It's not simple, clear, and easy.
まだ想像と妄想と偏見で Why
Why are you still full of imagination, delusions, and prejudice?
そりゃ完全な万全な設定じゃない
Well, that's not a perfectly complete setup,
からかってくれないか
so won't you tease me a bit?
外見と内面と偶像の不一致
A mismatch between appearance, inner self, and idol image.
この繊細さ敏感さを共有しよう
Let's share this delicacy and sensitivity.
ほら冷静な表情は実際ちょーハイ
Look, a calm expression is actually super hype!
見つけてくれないか
Won't you find me?
はいはいお姉さん しまっちゃって行こう
Yeah, yeah, big sister, let's wrap it up and go!
はいはい期待感 背負っちゃって行こう
Yeah, yeah, let's carry these expectations and go!
はいはいお姉さん しまっちゃって行こう
Yeah, yeah, big sister, let me wrap it up and go!
はいはい期待感 背負っちゃって行こう
Yeah, yeah, let's carry these expectations and go!
ホロホーク ホロホーク だけど
HoloHawk, HoloHawk, but...
高嶺の花みたいに扱っちゃ嫌
Don't treat me like an unattainable flower.
あのね 誰も彼も
You know, everyone and anyone
鷲と勘違い 驚きの目
mistakes me for an eagle with eyes full of surprise.
ホロホーク ホロホーク だけど
HoloHawk, HoloHawk, but...
PONコツみがちょいあるだけで親近感
Just a little clumsiness brings a sense of closeness.
その際 その差異 その才 受け止めてよね
That occasion, that difference, that talent—accept it all, okay?
鷹嶺の未来 乾杯
A toast to Takane's future!
ノーイーグル しっかりウォッチング
No Eagle, watch closely!
ノーイーグル 曖昧 You know
No Eagle, vague, you know?
ノーイーグル 狩りとか苦手
No Eagle, not good at hunting.
ノーイーグル 猛禽ルイ姉
No Eagle, raptor Sister Lui.
ノーイーグル 一見クールね
No Eagle, cool at first glance.
ノーイーグル 意外とギャップ系
No Eagle, surprisingly full of gap charm!
ノーイーグル イメージ大変身
No Eagle, a total image makeover!
ノーイーグル OK?
No Eagle, OK?
大衆の歓声って内蔵じゃない？
Isn't the cheering from the crowd built-in?
ありゃ心配ね 相談ね 散々ねもう
Oh, that's worrying, asking for advice, it's terrible already!
ただ正論や暴論の配信じゃない！
This isn't just a stream of sound logic or absurd arguments!
個人的見解対正解
Personal opinions vs. the correct answer!
ホロホーク ホロホーク だけど
HoloHawk, HoloHawk, but...
捕食しないさ だから怖がっちゃ嫌
I won't prey on you, so don't be afraid!
ほらね 爪も羽も
See? Both claws and feathers
お洒落に研いで 隠しちゃいない
are stylishly polished, nothing to hide!
ホロホーク ホロホーク だけど
HoloHawk, HoloHawk, but...
観察目がちょいあるだけで緊張感
Just an observant eye creates a sense of tension!
その際 その差異 その才 受け止めてよね
That occasion, that difference, that talent—accept it all, okay?
鷹まる時代 乾杯
A toast to an era of soaring high!
はいはいお姉さん しまっちゃって行こう
Yeah, yeah, big sister, let's wrap it up and go!
はいはい期待感 背負っちゃって行こう
Yeah, yeah, let's carry these expectations and go!
はいはいお姉さん しまっちゃって行こう
Yeah, yeah, big sister, let me wrap it up and go!
はいはい期待感 背負っちゃって行こう
Yeah, yeah, let's carry these expectations and go!
ホロホーク ホロホーク だけど
HoloHawk, HoloHawk, but...
高嶺の花みたいに扱っちゃ嫌
Don't treat me like an unattainable flower.
あのね 誰も彼も
You know, everyone and anyone
鷲と勘違い 驚きの目
mistakes me for an eagle with eyes full of surprise.
ホロホーク ホロホーク だけど
HoloHawk, HoloHawk, but...
PONコツみがちょいあるだけで親近感
Just a little clumsiness brings a sense of closeness.
その際 その差異 その才 受け止めてよね
That occasion, that difference, that talent—accept it all, okay?
鷹嶺の未来 乾杯
A toast to Takane's future!
愛じゃん 鷹まる時代 乾杯
It's love! A toast to an era of soaring high!
Sorry
To be late
Do you remember me?
魅了る目と目が合ったら
When our mesmerizing eyes meet,
きっと落下線 下へ
it's surely a trajectory falling downward.
足んない爪はもう真っ赤っ赤
Lacking nails are already bright red,
それは Wink off Wink off
that's Wink off, Wink off.
I'm Crazy な台風の目
I'm a crazy eye of the storm. Wink!
Showdown お目が高い
Showdown! You have good taste.
目に入れたって痛くないくらい
So precious I could put you in my eye without pain.
クチバシに Sweet Vengeance
Sweet vengeance on my beak.
憎しみならとっくに捨てた
If it's hatred, I threw that away long ago.
怖がってんの？
Are you scared?
あっそ
Oh, really?
Don't let me down
Eyes on me now
まだ まだ
Not yet, not yet.
安全じゃないから？
Because it's not safe?
健全じゃないから？
Because it's not wholesome?
それがなんだ
So what?
Franticだね
How frantic.
目には眼を
An eye for an eye.
バイバイ怨嗟
Bye bye, resentment
目に物見せる My EYE EYE
I'll show you what's what, My EYE EYE
Wink off
目を瞑る半分ね
Closing half an eye
魔眼ウインク
Demon Eye Wink
有能が絢爛降臨
Competence descends in glorious splendor
魔眼ウインク
Demon Eye Wink
My god My god
ほらご覧 瞬く間に
Look, in the blink of an eye
EYE EYE EYE
EYE'll kill you
Wink
後ろ指指したいなら お好きにどうぞ
If you want to point fingers behind my back, feel free
当方 当世振り返らぬ所存の金輪際
I have zero intention of ever looking back at this world
お待たせ Suck out Suck out
Thanks for waiting, Suck out Suck out
おさらば 恨み Cut Cut
Farewell, resentment Cut Cut
無礼講な祭り目
An uninhibited festive eye
I'm coming back coming back coming back
目じゃない 眼中茶飯
It's nothing, just everyday chatter
善良じゃないだろう
It's not good, is it?
最良じゃないだろう
It's not the best, is it?
それがどうしたんだ
So what about it?
Franticだね
How frantic
目には眼を
An eye for an eye,
歯には羽を
a feather for a tooth
La La La La La
C'est la la vie
類は何を呼ぶ?
What birds of a feather flock together?
C'est la vie 羽ばたき知るウインク
C'est la vie, a wink that knows how to flutter
目が離せない
I can't take my eyes off
完璧なウインク
A perfect wink
Say La La Lovin'
隻眼 Gimmick Gimme a wink
One-eyed gimmick, Gimme a wink
真っ赤赤な Oh EYE EYE EYE
Crimson red Oh EYE EYE EYE
EYE want you で バイバイ怨嗟
With EYE want you, bye bye resentment
目に物見せる My EYE EYE
I'll show you what's what, My EYE EYE
Wink off
もう目が離せない EYE EYE
I can no longer take my eyes off, EYE EYE
魔眼ウインク
Demon Eye Wink
My god My god
ほらご覧 瞬く間に
Look, in the blink of an eye
EYE EYE EYE
EYE'll kill you
La La La La...
Wink
弾けない
Can't play
なんてありえない
Is impossible
後に引けない
Can't back down
無闇にひけらかさない Fly...
Won't recklessly show off, Fly...
いつも突然のハラハラ
Always a sudden thrill
火花散れば命からがら
When sparks fly, barely escaping with our lives
待ったなしの媚びずダンシング
Non-stop, unapologetic dancing
強かなステップで交わしちゃうぜ
Dodging with sly steps
サラリーな社会が眠る頃に
When the salaried society goes to sleep
パラリラ輩跋扈するコロニー
In a colony where ruffians roam freely
持ちつ持たれつ表裏一体を
Mutual interdependence, two sides of the same coin
くぐり抜けて
Slipping through
平日はShoo be doo be do
On weekdays, Shoo be doo be do
週末もShoo be doo be do
On weekends too, Shoo be doo be do
時にきつくハードに 時に平和なバードみ
Sometimes harsh and hard, sometimes peaceful like a bird
今宵ひみつのおしごと
Tonight is secret business
綺羅煌々 狙ってBang ba bang
Glistening brightly, aiming Bang ba bang
外さないクリア
Never missing, clear
いざ堂々 目立ってRun and gun
Boldly standing out, Run and gun
未だに他に類を見ない
Still unprecedented
意気揚々 迫ってBang ba bang
Elatedly closing in, Bang ba bang
悟られずカバー
Covering without being noticed
Here we go yo 気取ってさぁ出番
Here we go yo, striking a pose, it's showtime
跡を濁さず Take off
Leaving no trace behind, Take off
けして逃がさない
Never letting them escape
剥いた牙を抜くまで
Until we pull out their bared fangs
けして汚さない
Never tarnishing
守る無二の看板
Protecting our unique banner
気取られない根回し Oh yeah
Undetected groundwork, Oh yeah
お見舞いする後の祭り Oh yeah
Delivering retribution too late to compensate, Oh yeah
響くヒールの音がお仕置きの合図
The echoing sound of heels is the signal for punishment
誰も 彼も Check out my ホークアイ
Everyone and anyone, check out my Hawk Eye
年始からShoo be doo be do
From the start of the year, Shoo be doo be do
年末もShoo be doo be do
To the end of the year, Shoo be doo be do
お任せあれハンドリング 表に出せない後処理
Leave the handling to us, dark cover-ups behind the scenes
もといひみつのおしごと
That is to say, secret business
綺羅煌々 狙ってBang ba bang
Glistening brightly, aiming Bang ba bang
外さないクリア
Never missing, clear
いざ堂々 目立ってRun and gun
Boldly standing out, Run and gun
しばしば類は友を呼ぶ
Birds of a feather often flock together
意気揚々 迫ってBang ba bang
Elatedly closing in, Bang ba bang
悟られずカバー
Covering without being noticed
Here we go yo 気取ってさぁ出番
Here we go yo, striking a pose, it's showtime
爪を剥き出し Beat you
Baring our claws, Beat you
たかが企業もどきと侮るのなら
If you look down on us as a mere pseudo-enterprise
タガが外れて容赦できなくなって やばっ! 炸裂!
Unfiltered and showing no mercy, oh no! Explosion!
本音かまし弱音なんてすぐねんね
Voicing our true feelings, weaknesses sleep fast
混じり気ないハートビート 揺らすこの世界
A pure heartbeat shaking this world
最果てまで届くよう鳴らした鐘
Ringing the bell to reach the farthest ends
裏の裏までいただいちゃおう
Let's take control of every hidden corner
綺羅煌々 狙ってBang ba bang
Glistening brightly, aiming Bang ba bang
外さないクリア
Never missing, clear
いざ堂々 目立ってRun and gun
Boldly standing out, Run and gun
未だに他に類を見ない
Still unprecedented
意気揚々 迫ってBang ba bang
Elatedly closing in, Bang ba bang
悟られずカバー
Covering without being noticed
Here we go yo 気取ってさぁ出番
Here we go yo, striking a pose, it's showtime
跡を濁さず Take off
Leaving no trace behind, Take off
Shoo be do be do
Hey!
今日もひみつの Take off
Taking off again today in secret
理不尽なこの反論に
To this unreasonable counterargument,
言葉付けて張ってっか
are you dressing it in words and putting up a front?
ねぇ 苛立った爪立てて
Hey, digging in your irritated claws,
信じられるものは
the only thing you can believe in
自分だけだと
is yourself, or so
思い込んで
you convince yourself,
進み続けて
and keep moving forward...
あの子みたいにすれば
If you try to act like that girl,
君じゃそれは無理だ
"That's impossible for you."
言わせておけばいいさ
Just let them talk!
だって1人 逆境の先
Because alone, beyond adversity,
相変わらず破格で
as extraordinary as ever,
私の邪魔 させやしない
I won't let anyone stand in my way!
咲かせてかね 見せてかね
Blooming or showing off, side by side,
仰ぎ見る空へと
Towards the sky I look up to,
飛んでいく
I fly up.
私を見ないなんて
Not looking at me...
BAD BOY
失敗は止まった時
Failure is when you stop,
今日も意地を張っての
so stubborn again today.
君の
Your...
ないものはないと
Insisting you have everything you need,
信じられるものを
until you find something to believe in,
見つけ出すまで
no matter what kind of day it is,
笑い飛ばすんだ
you just laugh it off!
あの子はもう終わりだ
"That girl is finished."
これ以上はないね
"There's nothing left for her."
言わせておけばいいさ
Just let them talk!
いつの日か目を覚ましても
Even if I wake up one day,
夢を見てちゃ届かない
merely dreaming won't reach it.
私は
I...
ここで死にたくない
don't want to die here!
一生の旅 逆境の先
A lifelong journey, beyond adversity,
相変わらず破格で
as extraordinary as ever,
私の邪魔 させやしない
I won't let anyone stand in my way!
咲かせてかね 見せてかね
Blooming or showing off, side by side,
仰ぎ見る空へと
Towards the sky I look up to,
飛んでいく
I fly up.
私を見ないなんて
Not looking at me...
BAD BOY
誰かに言われなくたって
Even if nobody tells me,
私のほうがもっと嫌いだ
I hate myself even more.
うるさいな
Shut up.
想像が視界を塞いで
Imagination blocks my vision,
惨めな理由を書き連ねる
listing miserable reasons one after another.
教室にずっと居残り
Staying behind in the classroom,
窓の向こうに黒い影があって
there was a dark shadow outside the window,
何も言わずにこっちを見ていた
staring at me without saying a word.
私は貴方に救われたくて泣くんじゃない
I'm not crying because I want you to save me.
産声は止められないもの
A newborn cry cannot be stopped.
何千回ともう一度死に損なおう
Let's survive death thousands of times and once more.
希望と絶望の夜中を纏って
Clad in a midnight of hope and despair,
醜い光を許したのは
The one who forgave that ugly light
他ならない私だった
was none other than myself.
息をして 目を開けて
Breathing in, opening my eyes...
これが最後かどうか
Whether this is the end or not,
知る術はないよ
there's no way to know,
知りたいともないよ
nor do I want to know.
優しいな
How gentle...
昏昏と闇は寄り添って
Deep darkness nestles close,
解けない答えを塗り潰した
painting over unsolvable answers.
「どうせ申し訳ないよ」と
"I'm sorry anyway,"
窓を挟んでかすかに聞こえた
I faintly heard through the window.
それは祈るような すすり泣きだった
It was a sob, almost like a prayer.
私はあなたを救える言葉を知らないけど
I don't know the words that could save you, but...
「寂しいね」と声をかけた
I reached out and said, "It feels lonely, doesn't it?"
何千回ともう一度 死に損なおう
Let's narrowly survive thousands of times and once more,
希望と絶望の夜中を纏って
cloaked in a midnight of hope and despair.
何千回ともう一度 息をあなたへ
Thousands of times and once more, sending my breath to you,
私も続くよ
I will follow as well,
窓の向こう側で
on the other side of the window.
醜い光を愛せたとき
When I was able to love that ugly light,
終わらせなかった産声を
the first cry I didn't let end...
歌にしよう
let's turn it into a song.
Let's turn it into a song.
歌にしよう
特報
[Special News]
戦う理由は、一つじゃない
There is more than one reason to fight.
鷹嶺ルイ 2nd ALBUM 『LAPIS LAZULI』 2025.12.03
Takane Lui 2nd Album 'LAPIS LAZULI' - 2025.12.03
全国CDショップにて予約開始！
Pre-orders now open at CD shops nationwide!
GAMERSにてリリース記念ミニライブ開催決定！
Release Commemorative Mini Live confirmed at GAMERS!
Stay Tuned.
はい、ということで、今特報を見ていただきましたが
Okay then! You just watched the special teaser,
なんと！鷹嶺ルイ、12月3日に、自身のセカンドアルバム『Lapis Lazuli』を発売することが決定しましたー！
and surprisingly, Takane Lui will be releasing her 2nd album "Lapis Lazuli" on December 3rd!
ふー！いぇーい！
Woo! Yeah!
ということで、なんとですね、今回は鷹嶺史上初の全国…全国のショップで買える全国流通盤ということで
So, surprisingly, for the first time in Takane history, this album will be available at CD shops nationwide!
えー、またひとつ夢が叶っちゃいました！みんなのおかげです、ありがとうー！
Ah, another one of my dreams has come true! It's all thanks to everyone, thank you!
えー、『1st』に続きまして、『Liberty』に続きましてセカンドなんですけども、今回は『Lapis Lazuli』というね、タイトルをつけさせていただきました。
Following '1st' and 'Liberty', this is my second album, and I titled it 'Lapis Lazuli'.
この『Lapis Lazuli』というのはですね、いつもあの、アルバムには「L」の文字がついてるんですけれどもし
As for 'Lapis Lazuli', my album titles always start with the letter "L"...
えー、今回も「L」の文字から始まる『Lapis Lazuli』という言葉で、えー、こちらですね、あの、意味がですね、「成功に導く」だったりとか
and this time as well, 'Lapis Lazuli' starts with "L", carrying meanings such as "guiding to success"...
あとは結構あの、「勝利へと…勝利を掴み取る」みたいな、えー、意味合いが込められておりまして
...or "grasping victory."
なんとこちらアルバムはですね、VS…「戦い」をテーマにした曲ばかりになっておりますので
And surprisingly, this album is packed with songs themed around "VS" and "battle"...
えー、そういった意味合いも込めて、『Lapis Lazuli』という名前をつけさせていただきました。
...so with those thoughts in mind, I named it 'Lapis Lazuli'.
さらに！なんとですね、秋葉原ゲーマーズ本店さんでもリリース記念ライブをやらせていただくことになりましたー！
Furthermore, we'll be holding a release commemorative mini-live at the Akihabara Gamers main store!
なんとミニライブも開催ということで
We're having a mini-live too!
えー、本日ですね、12時半から予約開始となっているので、もうすでに予約ができる状態になっております。
Pre-orders started today at 12:30, so they are open right now!
えー、皆さんもう見えますかね？画面の左下、左下にボタンありますか？皆ある？ボタン
Can everyone see it? At the bottom left of your screen, is there a button? Does everyone see the button?
あるかしら？
Is it there, I wonder?
そこからですね、購入ボタンがありますので、そこから予約ができるようになりましたので、ぜひぜひこちらから予約してみてください。
There's a purchase button there where you can pre-order, so please go ahead and give it a click!
ということで、アルバムの詳細をね、パッとお話しさせていただこうかなと思うんですけれども、おめでとー！ありがとうみんな！
Now, I'd like to quickly talk about the album details... thank you all for the congratulations!
収録楽曲についてはこちらになります。どどん！
Here are the included track listings. Ta-da!
はい、先行リリースしております『ZIG-ZAG』をはじめ、先ほども言いましたVS、戦いをテーマにした全10曲が収録されています。
Yes! Starting with the pre-released "ZIG-ZAG", all 10 songs are themed around VS and battle.
6曲目にはですね、皆さんお分かりですか？「featuring ラプラス・ダークネス」ということで
And track 6—can you tell?—features La+ Darknesss!
ラピスラズリ
Lapis Lazuli.
一緒に歌った曲も収録されております
Songs I sang together with others are also included.
そしてですね、色々と言いたいことはあるんですけども
And also, there's a lot I want to say about them,
一つ一つ言いたいんですけど、ちょっとお時間がないので
I want to talk about each one, but we're short on time, so...
10曲目の「抗う君への鎮魂歌」という曲はですね
Track 10, "Requiem for You Who Resist,"
とあるアニメのイメージソングになっておりますので
serves as an image song for a certain anime.
これから色々情報が出てくると思いますので
More details will be revealed going forward,
楽しみに待っていただければなと思います
so please look forward to it!
そして！
And next!
完全生産限定盤はこんな感じになっております！どうぞ！
Here is the Complete Production Limited Edition! Take a look!
お、どうぞ！あ、こっちだ！どうぞ！あ、こっちだ！
Oh, here! Ah, this way! Here! Ah, over here!
スライドボックス式でですね
It comes in a slide box specification,
二人の鷹嶺ルイを離したりくっつけたりできる
allowing you to separate or combine the two Takane Luis...
おしゃれでしょう？
Isn't that stylish?
しかも「Liberty」と同じ
Plus, just like with "Liberty",
SOLANIさんがイラストを担当してくださいましたー！
SOLANI-san illustrated it for us!
めちゃくちゃカッコよくないですか？
Doesn't it look super cool?
ぜひぜひね、戦わせたり離したりして
Definitely try posing them to fight or separate them,
遊んでみてください！
and have fun with it!
他にもこのようなグッズもございます！
In addition, we also have these merch items!
完全生産限定盤にはですね
Included in the Complete Production Limited Edition,
今までにリリースした楽曲のジャケットを入れ込んだ
we have put together all the cover art of my previously released songs into a...
ジャケットイラストブック！これね、私が欲しいって言ったんですよ！
...Jacket Illustration Book! I actually requested this myself!
無理やり「欲しい」って言ったんですけど
I pushed pretty hard saying I really wanted it,
なんと実現をしてくださりまして！
and amazingly, they made it happen!
今までにリリースした楽曲のジャケットが
So all the cover art from my releases up until now
一冊の本になって見れるやつになっております！
can now be viewed together in a single art book!
いや、みんな欲しかったでしょう？
I mean, you all wanted this too, right?
私画欲しいものはきっとみんなが欲しいと思ってですね
I figured if I wanted it, you guys definitely would too!
こちらちょっと無理やりに作っていただきました！
So I insistently asked them to make this happen!
ご協力してくださった関係者の皆さん、ありがとうございます！
Huge thanks to everyone on staff who helped fulfill this request!
そしてですね、オリジナル缶バッジも2種類ついて
Additionally, it comes with a set of 2 original pin badges...
そして！そして！
And! And!
今回もですね、完全生産限定盤に
Once again, available exclusively for the Complete Production Limited Edition...
だけになるんですけれどもの、直筆サイン入りジャケットカードを
...I will be signing each jacket card by hand
購入者全員！皆さんに！
for EVERY SINGLE PERSON who purchases it!
直筆サインさせていただきますので
Yes, every buyer gets a hand-signed card!
ぜひぜひ完全生産限定盤
So please do consider getting the Complete Production Limited Edition!
いろんな特典がありますので買っていただけますと幸いでございます
It comes loaded with special bonuses, so I'd be super grateful if you buy it!
さらに、通常盤はこちら！
Next, here is the Regular Edition!
はい！通常盤にはですね、ランダムアナザージャケット
Yes! The Regular Edition comes with a random alternate jacket card,
1枚入り、全5種類ある中の1枚が入っております
featuring 1 random card out of 5 collectible designs.
そして、こちらもですね、数量限定ランダムで
Also, in limited quantities, a random selection will feature
鷹嶺ルイの直筆サイン、そしてコメントもついてきます！
my handwritten autograph and personal message!
ちょっとこちらはランダムになっちゃうんですけれども
Though this one is a random draw,
ぜひぜひ皆さんに当たりますように！
I really hope good luck finds you all!
通常盤もぜひ買ってみてください！
Please consider picking up the Regular Edition too!
そしてそして、各ショップの法人特典はこちらになります！ドドン！
And next up, here are the store-exclusive retailer bonuses! Ta-da!
Amazon様マウスパッドだったり、色々なね
Like a mousepad from Amazon, and various other items...
お店で色んな特典がついておりますので
Each store offers different exclusive bonuses,
皆さん欲しいものがあればそちらで予約してくださると嬉しいでございます
so I'd be super happy if you pre-order wherever you find your favorite bonus!
また詳細などはポストしますので、そちらで詳しく見ていてください！
I'll also be posting the details on social media, so please check there for more info!
はい、さらにこちら！
Alright, and here's one more big announcement!
秋葉原ゲーマーズ本店さんにて、12月7日にリリース記念ミニライブの開催が決定いたしましたー！
As mentioned earlier, a special release commemoration mini-live will be held at Gamers Akihabara Main Store on December 7th!
ゲーマーズさんでアルバムを購入した人の中から抽選でミニライブにご招待をさせていただきます！
Customers who purchase the album at Gamers will be entered into a lottery to win invitations to the mini-live!
ぜひゲーマーズさんでもアルバムを買ってくださると嬉しいでございます！
So I'd be really glad if you buy the album through Gamers as well!
ということで、今回ですね、皆さんの左下にあるボタンではですね
With that said, using the button at the bottom left of your screen,
完全生産限定盤と通常盤のところにECサイトに飛ぶのかな？
clicking on the Complete Edition or Regular Edition will take you to the e-commerce site.
多分オフィシャルサイトに飛びますので、そちらで完全生産限定盤だったりが欲しいよっていう方はそちらで
It'll likely direct you to the official site, so if you'd like to get the Complete Limited Edition,
予約をしていただきまして、ちょっと他のショップさんで予約をしたいよという方はね
you can pre-order there! And for those wishing to pre-order from other retailers,
詳細、後ほどX、そして概要欄にも貼らせていただきますので
details will be posted later on X as well as linked in the description box,
そちらチェックをしていただけると嬉しいでございます！
so please check those out too!
いや、ラピスラズリ、しかもですね、ラピスラズリって誕生石が...
And you know, Lapis Lazuli is actually the birthstone...
9月と12月ということで
...for both September and December!
なんと9月に私重大発表をして、12月に発売っていうね
Amazingly, I made the major announcement in September, and it releases in December!
あ、これたまたまなんですけど、あ、まあ、たまたまって言わない方がいいよね
Ah, it was purely coincidental, though maybe I shouldn't call it a coincidence...
これね、仕掛けなんですねこれ！仕掛けさせていただきました！
No, it was totally planned from the start! I deliberately arranged it that way!
偶然じゃなくて、ちゃんと、ちゃんと考えました！
It wasn't by chance at all, I carefully, carefully planned it!
なので、私の夢であり...
So this album is a big dream of mine...
全国流通版の
The nationwide release of
2ndアルバム ぜひぜひ皆さんご購入いただけますと
my 2nd album! I'd be so happy if you all bought it,
幸いです よろしくお願いします
thank you so much!
それでは まだまだ歌っていきたいと思います
Now then, I'd like to keep on singing!
この後もまだまだ告知がございますので お楽しみに
There are still more announcements after this, so please look forward to them.
ちょっと水を飲んでもいいですか？ 水を飲んでもいいですね？
Can I drink some water? It's fine to drink water, right?
水を飲みます ちょっと待ってください
I'll drink water. Please wait a moment.
飲みました！
I drank it!
ということでね まだお一人
So then, there's still one...
ゲストが出てない方がいらっしゃいますね
guest who hasn't appeared yet.
その方はいつ出るんでしょうか
When will that person appear?
お見逃しなく！
Don't miss it!
ということで 続いての曲 行きましょうか
So then, shall we move on to the next song?
皆さん準備は大丈夫ですか？
Is everyone ready?
準備は大丈夫ですね それでは
Looks like you're ready. Well then...
はい それでは聴いてください「ZIG-ZAG」
Yes, please listen to "ZIG-ZAG."
1, 2, 3, 4!
ということで もう一人の特別ゲストを呼びたいと思います！
So, I'd like to invite our another special guest!
星街すいせい！
Hoshimachi Suisei!
盛り上がっていきましょう！
Let's get hyped!
「幸せ？」ってささやいた
"Are you happy?" you whispered.
こびりついて離れはダメ
Stuck fast, I shouldn't leave.
無味無臭の生活が思い出せないや
I can't even remember my tasteless, odorless life.
忘れたいから歌った
I sang because I wanted to forget.
怨むことも 嫉むことも 賢くないゆえ出来なかった
I couldn't bear grudges or envy because I wasn't smart enough.
結末ならば 笑ってしまいたい
If this is the ending, I'd rather just laugh.
ほど 嘘 嘘 嘘
Unto... Lie, lie, lie.
痛い 痛い 痛い 痛いな 奇跡とかちょっと望んじゃって
It hurts, hurts, hurts, hurts. Hoping for a miracle...
もう嫌 嫌 嫌 嫌 嫌 タッチが悪いわ
I hate it, hate it, hate it... Bad touch.
寝苦しいな おかしいとこ全部えぐりとって
Hard to sleep... Gouging out everything that's wrong.
薄情で結構 好きに呼んでいいよ
Cold-hearted is fine, call me whatever you like.
トラウマにバイバイしたいのです
I just want to say goodbye to trauma.
私 甘え上手になれなかった 可愛げとかが足りなかった 後悔がうるさい夜だ
I couldn't learn to act sweet, lacking charm. Regrets are so loud tonight.
過去は過去だと割り切っちゃえば きっといいことあるさとか それくらい 100も承知だ
"If you move past the past, good things will happen." I know all that perfectly well.
願うことも 祈ることも 許されないから黒く染めた
Neither wishing nor praying was allowed, so I dyed it black.
元の色も思い出せない
I can't even remember its original color.
からだ 運命の糸
Body... Threads of fate.
痛い 痛い 痛い 痛いな 悲劇のヒロイン気取っちゃって
It hurts, hurts, hurts, hurts. Acting like a tragic heroine...
もう嫌 嫌 嫌 嫌 嫌 諦めてちゃえば
I hate it, hate it, hate it... If I just give up...
でも痛い 痛い 痛い 痛いな 思考回路こんがらがっちゃって
But it hurts, hurts, hurts, hurts. My train of thought is all tangled up.
明日またきっと壊すけどいいの
I'll probably break it again tomorrow, but is that okay?
トラウマ再発したいのです
I want my trauma to recur.
夢の中で君と 手をつないでいるの
In my dreams, holding hands with you...
何も知らないあの頃の二人のままで
Remaining as the two of us back when we knew nothing.
でも解っているよ すぐに覚めてしまうと
But I know that I'll awaken soon enough.
それならばいっそ 君の手でそっと とどめ刺して ほら 今 今 今
If so, then rather, finish me off softly with your hands. Look, now, now, now!
痛い 痛い 痛い 痛いな 奇跡とかちょっと望んじゃって
It hurts, hurts, hurts, hurts. Hoping for a miracle...
もう嫌 嫌 嫌 嫌 嫌 タッチが悪いわ
I hate it, hate it, hate it... Bad touch.
寝苦しいな おかしいとこ全部えぐりとって
Hard to sleep... Gouging out everything that's wrong.
薄情で結構 好きに呼んでいいよ
Cold-hearted is fine, call me whatever you like.
トラウマにバイバイしたいのです
I just want to say goodbye to trauma.
すいちゃん来てくれてありがとう！
Sui-chan, thank you for coming!
いやールイちゃん楽しかったぜー！
Ah, Lui-chan, that was so much fun!
いやー嬉しいぜー！
Ah, I'm so happy!
ジグザグジグザグ
Zig-zag, zig-zag!
ということで皆さんに すいちゃんが来てくれました！
So everyone, Sui-chan has joined us!
来ましたよー！
I'm here!
彗星の如く現れたスターの原石 バーチャルアイドルの星街すいせいです！
It's the rough diamond of a star that appeared like a comet, virtual idol Hoshimachi Suisei!
すいちゃんはー？
How is Sui-chan today?
今日にも可愛いー！
Cute today as well!
ありがとうございますー！
Thank you so much!
ということで ルイ 2ndアルバム発売決定おめでとう！
So then, Lui, congratulations on the announcement of your 2nd album!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
いや、いっぱいあの... いっぱい、いっぱい相談しました。
Yeah, I consulted with her a lot... really a lot.
確かろろ聞いたかも！なんか曲結構知ってるかも！
Indeed, I might've heard about it! I feel like I actually know quite a few of the songs!
そう、いっぱい、いっぱい相談しました、すいちゃんに。
Right, I consulted with Sui-chan a lot.
この「ジグザグ」もね、実はちょっとリリース前から聴いてて。
Actually, I had been listening to "ZigZag" since before its release too.
はい。今日、そう、今日はですね、「ジグザグ」をすいちゃんと歌いたかった理由はですね...
Yes. Today, the reason why I wanted to sing "ZigZag" with Sui-chan is...
まぁ、本当にあの、いっぱい、いっぱい相談をしたっていうのの...
Well, it's because I consulted with her so much, and...
あと曲がね、タイトルのを一緒にね、考えてくれたんですよね。「ジグザグ」という...
also because we brainstormed the song title together, right? "ZigZag"...
そうなんですよ！一番最初、タイトル本当は違ったんだよね。
That's right! Originally, the title was actually different, right?
そう、そうなんですよ。 / うん、そこから「どうかな〜」つって... 「え？ジグザグってトラウマって意味あるらしいよ」みたいな...
Yeah, that's right. / Yeah, from there we were like "How about this?" and "Wait, apparently 'zigzag' can mean trauma," or something like that...
なって、一緒にね、「え、ジグザグ良くない？」「間ハイフンとか入れようぜ」とかつって。 / 「おしゃれじゃない？」みたいな。
And then together we were like, "Hey, isn't 'ZigZag' great?" "Let's put a hyphen in between." / "Isn't that stylish?"
そう！な、な、たくさん、たくさん相談をしまして。
Right! So we talked and consulted a lot...
でね、「ジグザグ」すいちゃんに合いそうだな、みたいな。
And I felt like "ZigZag" would really suit Sui-chan.
え、でもこれね、歌っててね... 楽しいね！
But you know, singing this song... it's so much fun!
楽しいでしょう！ / これ楽しいですよ、すごく！
It's fun, right! / This is really fun!
楽しいんですよ。 / しかもルイとね、やっぱその声質というか、この、なんだろ、低音歌う組というか...
It really is. / Plus, with Lui, our voice types—or how should I say—as part of the low-register singing group...
として、なんか合ってるなっていうのもすごい思ったし。だから歌ってて楽しかったです。
I really felt that our voices matched well. So it was really fun singing together.
いや、もう「ジグザグ」歌うんだったら、すいちゃんと歌いたいって言って...
Yeah, I said if I was going to sing "ZigZag," I definitely wanted to sing it with Sui-chan...
もう、「絶対すいちゃんと歌う！」って言って...
I was like, "I'm definitely singing this with Sui-chan!"
ね、あの、呼び出したら快諾をしてくださいました。本当にありがとうございます、お忙しい中で！
And when I asked her, she willingly agreed. Thank you so much, even while being so busy!
いやいや、そんなもう！生出演なんてもう、いつでも呼んでくださいよ！そんなね！
No, no, not at all! For live guest appearances, feel free to invite me anytime!
ありがとうございます！ / コメントの皆さんもね！
Thank you so much! / Everyone in the comments too!
はい、どうもどうも！あ、いい！かっこいいかっこいい、合ってる合ってる！分かる分かるって、ほらね言ってるね。
Yes, hello hello! Ah, nice! Cool, cool, it fits! "I get it, I get it," see, they're saying it!
いや本当に、一緒に歌えて... 本当に緊張したんだけど、一緒に歌えて良かった！しかも2回目なんですよ、2人で歌ったの。 / そうなんですね！
Really, being able to sing together... I was really nervous, but I'm so glad we sang together! And this is actually our second time singing as a duo. / Is that so!
そう、そうなんですよ。MGAのファーストでね。 / 『バグ』。
Yeah, that's right. At MGA's first... / "Bug".
そう、『バグ』で。 / 今度は『ジグザグ』。 / 『ジグザグ』。
Yeah, with "Bug". / This time it's "ZigZag". / "ZigZag".
次は何になるんでしょうか？ / 次は何グですか？何グになるんでしょうか？
What will be next? / What "-g" will be next? What "-g" will it end up being?
ね、今後も楽しみにしていただけたらなと思うんですけれども...
Right, I hope everyone looks forward to the future, but...
なんと！まだ告知があるんです！ / え？
What's more! There's still an announcement! / Huh?
そんな、まさか！ / はい。なので...
No way! / Yes. So...
え？え？ / どんなやつ...
Huh? Huh? / What kind of...
え？ちょっと、この... このアルバムに絡めた... やつですよ。
Eh? Well, a... something related to this album.
ええっ？！何々？！気になる気になる！ / 気になる？じゃあ一緒に見ようか。
EH?! What is it?! I'm curious, I'm curious! / Curious? Then shall we watch it together?
え、見るんだ。 / そう、一... 一緒に見よう。 / はい。
Eh, we get to watch it? / Yes, let's... let's watch it together. / Okay.
ということで、こちらをご覧ください！どうぞ！
So, please take a look at this! Go ahead!
特報
[Special Announcement]
おや はて さて 存じ上げないわ
Oh, well now, I have no idea who you are.
え、わっ
Eh, woah!
Who are you, you, you, you どちら様？
Who are you, you, you, you, who might you be?
Face to face こんにちは You are me?
Face to face, hello, you are me?
もうなんてったって Up side down for 自分、自分
After all, everything is upside down for myself, myself.
Look-alike ない グラグラ ラカラカラ
Look-alike, no, wobbling, rattling around.
通りゃんせ てかお前 てかお前 てかお前は
Pass through... I mean, who are you, who are you, who are you!?
昨日の自分は自分の手で片付けましょう
Let me clean up yesterday's self with my own hands.
てか Who are you? 誰？
I mean, who are you? Who?
このあと Original Anime MV 公開！
[Original Anime MV releasing right after this!]
なんと！セカンドアルバムより『DARE!?』が本日24時に先行デジタルリリースがされます！ / 『DARE!?』
What's more! "DARE!?" from my second album will be pre-released digitally today at midnight! / "DARE!?"
誰？誰誰誰？ / え、これ誰？え、こっちのルイは分かるけど、こっちのルイは誰ー？！
"DARE?" Who, who, who, who? / Wait, who is this? I recognize this Lui, but who is THIS Lui?!
誰なんだろう〜？ / 誰なんだろう〜？ / え、気になるよね〜？ / 気になるね〜！
Who could it be~? / Who could it be~? / You're curious, right~? / I'm curious~!
実は、この曲作った人も気にならない？ / え、気になる！
Actually, aren't you curious who made this song too? / Yeah, I am!
なんと、『まがまが WINK』を作ってくれたてにをはさんが今回も作成してくれたよ〜！
Surprise! Teniwoha, who made "Magamaga WINK," created this one for me as well~!
あ〜！てにをは節、確かに感じる！ / 感じるよね！ / 感じる、感じる！めちゃ感じ！
Ah~! I definitely feel that Teniwoha vibe! / You feel it, right! / Totally, totally! I feel it big time!
そして、この配信終了... 終了後には MV が公開されます！ / わあー！
And right after... right after this stream ends, the MV will be released! / Waaah!
え、MV、さっき流れてたやつですか？ / そうなんですよ。なんとあの... 鷹嶺ルイ史上... 今回鷹嶺ルイ史上いっぱいあるんだけど... 鷹嶺ルイ史上初の...
Eh, is the MV the one playing just now? / That's right! Surprisingly, a first in Takane Lui history... though there are many "firsts in Takane Lui history" this time... a first in Takane Lui history...
オリジナルアニメ MV、フルアニメ MV を作らせていただきました！ / わぁー！すごかった！めっちゃぬるぬる動いてた！
We created an original full anime MV! / Woah! That was amazing! It was moving so smoothly!
ぬるぬる動いてたでしょ？しかも、なんか、私が好きそうな絵のタッチじゃない？ / あ〜、確かにね！
It moved super smoothly, right? And plus, isn't it an art style that looks right up my alley? / Ah, true!
なんと私ですね、かねてより MV 作っていただきたいなと思っていた、安田現象さんに... / あの？！ / あの安田現象さんに！
Believe it or not, I had Yasuda Gensho—whom I've wanted to make an MV for me for a long time— / THAT one?! / THAT Yasuda Gensho!
あの安田現象さんですか？！ / そうなんです！ / 大丈夫ですか？！
THAT Yasuda Gensho?! / Yes, exactly! / Is it really okay?!
はい、あの…
Yes, um...
やすだ現象さんに作成をしていただいたフルアニメーションMVとなっております！
This is a full animation MV created for me by Yasuda Phenomena!
わあ、すごい！ サムネも可愛い！
Wow, amazing! The thumbnail is cute too!
可愛いでしょう？
Isn't it cute?
あっ、あっかんべーしてます。
Ah, she's sticking her tongue out.
あっかんべーしてるね。
She is sticking her tongue out, yeah.
ということで、このね、「DARE」というのは…
So, this "DARE" (Who) means...
内面にいる、まあ、私の中の…私、結構内面にアンチを持ってるんですけど…
The inner... well, within me... I actually have an "anti" inside me...
あ、そうなんだ。
Oh, really?
高嶺ルイのアンチを持っているんですけども…
I have an anti against Takane Lui inside me...
「お前本当にこれ出来んのか？」みたいなね。
Like, "Can you really do this?"
おー。
Oh.
「お前本当にやれんのか？」みたいな…
Or "Can you actually pull this off?"
「えっ？この感情って誰なん？」みたいな。
Like, "Wait, who is this feeling?"
おー。
Oh.
「えっ、私…私なの？何で私は私を否定してるの？」みたいな…
"Wait, is it me? Why am I denying myself?" like that...
そういうね、「誰？」っていう…
That kind of "Who?"...
深い！
Deep!
そういう楽曲に仕上がっておりますし、それを…
That's the kind of song it turned out to be, and...
てか「誰」って言うて…
Wait, saying "Who?"...
誰？
Who?
誰なの？私…
Who is it? Me...
という曲になっておりますので、これからちょっとMVもね、
So it's a song like that. We'll be premiering the MV after this...
プレミア公開させていただきますので、ぜひぜひ楽しんでいただければなと思いますし、結構耳に残るサウンドになってますので…
So I hope everyone enjoys it! The sound is really catchy too...
ね、もう今後ろで良いの流れてますけど。
Right, such a cool track is playing in the background already!
えっ、早くフル聴きたいし、なんなら今から歌ってもらえません？
Wow, I want to hear the full song soon. Actually, why don't you sing it right now?
えっ？えっ、何？
Eh? What?
えっ、一緒に歌いますか？
Wait, will you sing with me?
えっ？あ…
Eh? Ah...
うんと、チャチャチャッチャッ、ウッ、ヘイ！ヘイ！
Um, cha-cha-cha-cha, uh, hey! Hey!
歌いなさそうですね。
Doesn't look like she's going to sing.
ということで、この後実は「DARE!?」を先行で歌わせていただきまーす！
So! After this, I'm actually going to sing "DARE!?" early for you all!
わー！そうなの！？
Whoa! Really?!
じゃあ、私は端から見てますということで。
Then I'll be watching from the side!
待っててね、あの、ご飯食べ…ご飯食べよう一緒に。
Wait for me, okay? Let me... let's grab food together after.
あ、分かった分かった。じゃあ舞台袖で見物してますわ。
Ah, got it, got it. I'll watch from the side of the stage then!
この後じゃあご飯ということで、よろしくお願いします！
So food after this! Looking forward to it!
てか、フー・アー・ユー？誰？じゃあ！
By the way, who are you? Who? Bye then!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you so much!
すいちゃんでした！ありがとうみんなー！ありがとう！
That was Sui-chan! Thank you everyone! Thank you!
ということで、心強かった助っ人すいちゃんもいなくなり…
So, with my reassuring helper Sui-chan gone...
私1人でですね、新曲「Lapis lazuli」にも入っております曲「DARE!?」を歌わせていただきます！
I will now be singing "DARE!?", a track included in my new album "Lapis lazuli", all by myself!
ちょっと水飲んでいいですか？
Can I drink some water?
水飲みますよ。水飲みます。
I'm gonna drink water. Drinking water.
はい！
Okay!
ということで、戻ってまいりました。
So, I'm back!
それでは皆さん、聴いてください。「DARE!?」
Everyone, please listen. "DARE!?"
dare 誰？ そちら様 どちら様？ はて さてと
Who's who? Who might you be? Well, well, now...
フーアーユー？ ハウアーユー？ お元気で 一足お先に
Who are you? How are you? Hope you're well, I'll be taking my leave ahead!
てか フーアーユー？
I mean, who are you?
昨日のジブンが描いた円から はみ出さないように
So as not to stray beyond the circle yesterday's self drew,
ひとまわり小さな円を描くような
as if drawing an even smaller circle within,
ボールのバウンドが少しずつ低くなる様を
watching the bounce of the ball gradually grow lower,
術もなく眺めているような気分でしょ？ アハ
feeling helpless as you gaze at it—that's how you feel, right? Aha.
ところで アナタ
By the way... you.
dare？ dare？ dare？
Who? Who? Who?
おや はて さて 存じ上げないわ
My, my, well now... I have no idea who you are.
フーアーユー？ ユー ユー ユー どちら様？
Who are you? You, you, you, who might you be?
face to face コンニチハ
Face to face, hello!
ユーはミー？ もうなんてったって up side down for ジブン ジブン
Are you me? I mean, upside down for myself, myself!
look alike 雷雨 落雷
Lookalike, thunderstorm, lightning strike,
落下 落花生 とおりゃんせ
falling petals, falling buds, pass on through!
てか オマエ てか オマエ てか オマエは dare！？
I mean, you... I mean, you... I mean, who are you!?
昨日のジブンは自分の手で片付けましょう
Let's clean up yesterday's self with our own hands!
てか フーアーユー？ dare！？
I mean, who are you? Who!?
look alike and... look alike alike alike me！
Lookalike... Lookalike, alike, alike me!
昼夜問わず私が私のこと見張り続けてる
Day or night, I keep watching over myself...
なのでグッと背筋伸ばし微笑むの キャハ
So I stand tall, stretch my spine, and smile... kyaha!
花は誰に見られずとも美しく咲くと言うけど
They say flowers bloom beautifully even if no one sees them,
風や虫にもそっぽ向かれたら咲き方を改めるだろう
but if even the wind and bugs turn away, they'd change how they bloom, right?
dare dare？ dare！？
Who, who? Who!?
存じ上げないわ dare？
I have no idea... who?
フーアーユー？ ユー ユー ユー どちら様？
Who are you? You, you, you, who might you be?
face to face コンバンハ
Face to face, good evening!
ユーはミー？ もうなんてったって up side down for ジブン ジブン
Are you me? I mean, upside down for myself, myself!
look alike 雷雨 落雷
Lookalike, thunderstorm, lightning strike,
落下 落花生 とおりゃんせ
falling petals, falling buds, pass on through!
まいったまいわ 誰
I'm at a loss, who is it?
明日の私よ 私を倒せ
Tomorrow's me, defeat me!
てか フーアーユー? ハウアーユー? ハウアバウトユー? DARE!?
I mean, who are you? How are you? How about you? DARE!?
DARE!?
look alike...
me!
DARE だ DARE? そちら様 どちら様? はてさてと
Who, who is it? Who are you? Well, well then...
これ は DARE だ? DARE であれ 見せつけるだけ
Who is this? Whoever it is, I'll just show off!
take a look my dare
have a nice dare
はいということで、本日のライブはこれにて終了となります！
So with that, today's live stream comes to an end!
皆さん本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you all so very much!
改めて告知をさせていただきます
Allow me to make an announcement once again.
2ndアルバム『Lapis lazuli』が12月3日に発売されます！
My 2nd album, "Lapis lazuli," will be released on December 3rd!
予約はもう出来ますので
Pre-orders are already available,
こちらから是非是非予約をしてください！
so please pre-order right over here!
もうすごく頑張った…
I worked really hard on it...
頑張って頑張って歌った楽曲ばかりになりますので
It's filled with songs that I sang my absolute best for,
是非是非早く皆さんに聴いていただきたいなと思いますので
so I really want you all to listen to them as soon as possible.
是非2ndアルバムもよろしくお願いします！
Please support my 2nd album as well!
そして、豪華なスライドボックスパッケージで
And in a deluxe slide box package,
イラストブックや缶バッジ、直筆サイン入りのジャケットカードなどがついてくる完全生産限定盤
we have the Limited Edition featuring an art book, badges, and an autographed jacket card!
そして、ランダムアナザージャケット全5種から1枚
Also, 1 of 5 random alternative jackets,
数量限定ランダムで直筆サインとメッセージがつく通常盤
plus a Standard Edition with limited random autographed notes!
各種法人特典も盛りだくさんでございます
There are also plenty of retailer-exclusive bonus items!
秋葉原ゲーマーズ本店さんにて
At the Gamers Akihabara main store,
リリース記念のミニライブもやる予定でございます！
I'm also planning to hold a release commemoration mini-live!
そして、先ほど歌いました『DARE!?』が本日24時にデジタルリリースされますし
And "DARE!?", which I just sang, will be released digitally tonight at midnight!
この後すぐフルアニメーションMVも公開されます！
Right after this, a full-animation MV will also be released!
このままね見ていただければ…
If you stay right here and keep watching...
自動で、確か自動で（笑）
It'll automatically—I think automatically (laughs)—
MVに飛びますので、ぜひぜひフルアニメーション…
jump to the MV! So please check out the full animation...
私自身初のフルアニメーションになっておりますので
This is my very first full-animation music video,
ぜひ、可愛く仕上がったので見ていただけると嬉しいでございます
so I'd be super happy if you watch it since it turned out so cute!
はい！今回重大告知ライブということで
Right! Since today was a major announcement live stream,
皆さん「ソロライブなんじゃないか」って
everyone was guessing, "Is it a solo live concert?!"
すごい予想をしてくださっていたんですけれども
Many of you were making predictions like that,
私はですね、まだソロライブは決まっておりません！（笑）
but for me, a solo live concert isn't set yet! (laughs)
ですがですね、私音楽をやりたいと心に決めてからですね
But ever since I made up my mind that I wanted to do music,
夢であるファーストアルバムがリリース出来たり
I was able to release my dream 1st album,
そしてファーストアルバムを皆さんが買ってくださったから
and because everyone bought my 1st album,
こうやって2ndアルバムを全国流通として発売することが出来ました
I'm able to release this 2nd album nationwide!
1000万回再生のMVが2つも出来ましたし
I even got two MVs with over 10 million views,
その他の楽曲もたくさんたくさんみんなに愛してもらって
and so many of my other songs have been loved by everyone,
再生数もすごい伸びて
with view counts growing so much.
もうみんなのおかげでですね、私こんなに音楽をやっていて良かったなと
It's all thanks to everyone that I feel so glad to be making music!
今でも、そしてこれからもきっと想うと思います
I feel that way now, and I'm sure I will continue to feel that way.
ソロライブ、次は夢を一つずつ叶えてきたからこそ
As for a solo live, since we've been fulfilling my dreams one by one,
次はもう、ソロライブしかないやろ！（笑）
next up, it's gotta be a solo live!
なので必ず皆さんと一緒にソロライブを
So I definitely want to dream of a solo live concert
夢見て、みんなと一緒にまたここから走り出したいなと思います
together with everyone, and start running again from here!
ぜひぜひ皆さん、ファーストに引き続き2ndアルバムも
So everyone, following the 1st album, I'd be so happy
お手元に取っていただけると嬉しいです
if you could pick up a copy of the 2nd album as well!
なので、これからまた鷹嶺ルイと一緒にソロライブを目指しましょう！
So from now on, let's aim for that solo live together with Takane Lui!
目指してくれますか？
Will you aim for it with me?
ん？ ん？
Hmm? Hmm?
目指してくれるか？（笑）
Will you aim for it with me? (laughs)
もちろん！ええ、ありがとう！
Of course! Ah, thank you!
もう本当にみんなの力がないと、私はきっとソロライブに
Without everyone's power, I surely won't be able to
到達出来ないと思うので、私も頑張りますが
reach a solo live concert. I'll do my best too,
みんなも一緒に走り続けていただけると嬉しいです
but I'd be so happy if you keep running alongside me!
ルイ友の皆、そしてルイのことは2番手3番手ぐらいに推してるよというみんな（笑）
My Luitomo, and those of you who support me as your 2nd or 3rd fave (laughs),
そしてホロリスの皆さん、そしてこれからまた出会うであろう
all Holo-listeners, and everyone I have yet to meet
鷹嶺ルイを知っていただける皆さん
who will come to know Takane Lui,
皆さんの協力が必要ですのでぜひ…
I need everyone's help, so please...
是非是非これからも鷹嶺ルイをよろしくお願いします。
Please continue to support Takane Lui in the future!
はい、ということで
Alright, so with that...
じゃ、次のね、ま、次重大告知があるときには、もう超重大告知としてね
Next time there's an important announcement, I'll make it a "super important announcement"!
そのライブが発表できるように、これからも頑張ります！
I'll keep working hard so I can announce a live show like that!
みんな本当に今日はありがとう！
Everyone, thank you so much for today!
セカンドアルバムも楽しみにしててね。これからどんどん情報が出てくると思いますので
Look forward to the second album as well! More information will be released soon,
お楽しみに！またね！
so please stay tuned! See you!